All right. Uh, good to see everyone. Um,
before we get, you know, to questions,
uh, just want to take a moment to
recognize,
uh, all the people that are involved in
the draft process. Uh, our scouts, our
football ops, medical,
uh, the coaching staff. Uh, there's a
lot of hard work and dedication
um, that goes into this. a lot of time
away from families. Um, so I just want
to recognize that and tell everybody,
you know, thanks for that. Uh, we got a
great team. Um, we're really excited
about where we're headed, uh, with the
draft. Um, we're nine days away now. Um,
I really like where our where our
board's at right now. I think we're in a
good good spot right now. I think we're
going to be ready. I know we're going to
be ready for all scenarios that may
present themselves at pick 19.
Um, a lot of good players in this draft,
a lot of guys that we like and that
we're excited about. So, uh, it's going
to be fun and and we're looking forward
to that. Uh, I just want to mention, uh,
we're looking forward to, you know, the
fans being out there. We're having a
walk outside with our first rounder the
day after the draft. Um, so that'll
that'll be a lot of fun. Uh, look
forward to seeing a lot of the fans out
there uh to greet to greet our first
round pick. Um, you know, I know that
obviously he'll appreciate it and I
think uh the fans coming out here and
and people greeting him. I I think it's
going to be uh a lot of fun and and
we'll definitely appreciate it and and I
know the organization that will
definitely appreciate it. So, uh, also
beyond the draft, we're excited, you
know, to get our guys back in the
building under one roof. Uh, we start
the offseason program. Uh, so we're
excited about getting the guys back in
the building. I know a lot of the guys
already been in here working out. Uh,
guys look great. A lot of guys offsite
right now working out. Guys are working
their butts off. There's a lot of
excitement around the building. Um,
we're certainly excited where we're
headed. the direction that we're headed
as a franchise and as an organization.
So, uh, with that, I'll open it up to
any questions.
>> Dan, how different of of an exercise is
this for you guys from where you were
picking at eight and then when you were
picking at 33 entering uh, day one of
the draft the last two years?
>> Yeah, I mean, I think it's a little
different picking, you know, on the back
half of the of the first round. Um, but
it's really no different in terms of the
process. I mean, we're going to be ready
for any and all scenarios that present
themselves. Uh, you don't know what gu
is going to fall. Um, you know, a lot of
things can happen on unexpected. So, we
just got to be ready for any and all
scenarios and and that's what we've been
doing in the draft room every single day
is just planning for that and and
getting ready. I know we've asked you a
lot about NIL and its impact on the
draft, but how much do you weigh the age
and potential second contract situation
with the first round pick as well as
injuries to especially notable ones
entering Thursday?
>> Yeah. Um, you I think you definitely
have to weigh it. I think it's
definitely part of the evaluation
process. Um, but I also don't think it's
everything and it doesn't, you know,
take a guy out of the running because
maybe he's 25, 26 years old. So, um,
yeah, it's definitely something that we,
you know, weigh in. Um, but it's it's
not everything.
>> In January, you said you guys were going
to pick up Bryce's fifth year. Will you
wait and do that after the draft or
what's the timeline for that?
>> Yeah. Yeah, we'll uh once the draft's
over, we'll we'll definitely get that
going.
>> You guys have kind of done that the last
few years, Icky, JC.
If you know you're going to do it, why
wait? Just from like the standpoint of,
hey, you've made a decision already.
>> Well, you know, I think uh obviously the
player's not in the building yet, so you
know, once once Brace gets in the
building and uh you know, we're busy
with the draft. It's off seasonason, you
know, so we'll get that done as soon as
he gets back in the building.
>> Dan, the other week at the owners
meetings, Dave said something about at
19, he doesn't think you can necessarily
draft for depth. What does that mean to
you?
>> Um,
you know, I I think, you know, I
understand what coach is saying in terms
of obviously you want your first round
pick to be able to come in and
contribute immediately. Um, so yeah, I'm
kind of with him on that. uh you you
want your first round pick to play, but
you know there's different scenarios to
where you know maybe it takes a guy a
little longer to develop um and he may
you know may not contribute right away
but um you know with some of the picks
at different positions you know it may
take you know a little longer for those
guys to develop for sure.
what you guys did in free agency. Did
that do you think that narrowed your
focus positionally for 19 or does it
>> No, I think if anything I think it opens
opens us up to a lot of possibilities at
pick 19. Um, you know, I think all
positions are on the table and like I
said before like you never know who's
going to fall fall down to us. So, uh, I
think we're definitely in the best
player available mindset. Um, so yeah, I
think what we did in free agency
definitely set us up to do that. Dan,
obviously with uh your decision to
eventually pick up Bryce Young's uh
fifth year option, um this is an really
important year for Bryce and for this
offense. How um much of a priority is it
to get an extra playmaker on offense for
him specifically?
>> Um you know, I think uh you know, every
year is important for everybody,
including myself. Uh we we want to win.
We're all committed to winning. Um you
know, I think you know, Bryce is no
different. you know, myself is no
different. You know, we all are
committed to winning. We all want to
win. That's the ultimate goal is to win
a Super Bowl. Um bring a championship
back here to to Charlotte. Um you know,
in terms of playmakers, yeah, of course,
we always want to add as many playmakers
as you can on both sides of the ball,
not just, you know, a receiver. So, um,
I think, you know, when we talk about
the type of guys that we want to bring
in here, we want guys that make plays.
You know, whether it's a DB taking the
ball away or it's a receiver, running
back scoring touchdowns, we want guys
that are going to come in here and be
playmakers.
>> I've heard you and Dave reference really
wanting to know more about a player's
story in addition to all of the facts
and figures and stats. When did you
adopt that as a priority in this
process? Um, you know, I think uh I
think really us getting to know guys.
Um, you know, myself, Coach Canales,
Brandt, our scouting staff, like when
we're talking through guys, you know, I
I feel like if you're going to miss on a
guy, you're going to miss because you
don't know the guy. You don't know what
he's about from a personal character
standpoint, and you don't know what he's
about from a football standpoint. So, we
want to find out as much as we can about
these guys as possible. Um, understand
how passionate they are about the game.
Uh, what they do, what they like to do
away from the game, like where are they
spending their time away from the
facility. Um, so I think all aspects of
the player, we just want to know, get as
much information as possible.
>> To follow up on that, the the kind of
the why of each player, how important is
that when you're scouting quarterbacks?
I know you brought up wanting to have a
developmental quarterback
in in scouting these guys during the
process. How is how important is it to
understand what makes them tick and how
they can do that backup or third string
job for a couple?
>> Yeah, I think you know when you're when
you're a backup or, you know, even like
a third string guy, I think those type
of guys that you want to bring in are
guys that are going to support Bryce and
and guys that also are competitors and
they want to try to take Bryce's job,
you know, per se. So we we want guys
that are very supportive as teammates,
but we also want guys, you know, that
are going to come in and and they want
to compete and they want to be great.
>> When we talked to Brent, he talked about
the three phases of building a team. I
think he said building, contending,
sustaining. Said he felt like you guys
are in between building and contending.
How do you quantify that? And then how
as you approach the draft, how do you um
look to move from building to um
contending?
>> I mean, I think, you know, our goal
every year is to be a contender. Um
that's the ultimate goal. Uh we're all
here because we want to win. We all want
to win. We're passionate about this team
and this organization. Um, so in terms
of the building part, like yeah, we're
building a team. We're putting a team
together, but the ultimate goal is for
us to all compete um at a high level,
everybody to give their best every
single day, and that's towards the
ultimate goal, which is to win a
championship.
>> Would you say you guys are still in the
building phase or would you agree with
his assessment? I would say we're in the
phase to where we're continuing to add
good players and and competing. You
know, I think we have a locker room full
of competitive guys that are hungry to
win. We're hungry to win upstairs,
downstairs, around the building. Um, so
yeah, I'm definitely not going to box us
into we're building this thing. Yeah,
we're always going to be building this
thing, but make make no mistake like
we're we're in the mindset of going out
there competing and competing to not
just compete, but to win championships.
>> Dan, we've seen Joe Gilbert at a lot of
the offensive tackle pro days. Yeah.
>> Some of the big names. How how big a
priority is that position specifically
at 19?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, we we send position
coaches, not just Joe Gilbert, to
different pro days. So, it's not like,
hey, we're just going to see all these
offensive linemen. We're taking an
offensive lineman at 19 or 51. Um, so
yeah, I think the big thing is to,
again, going back to what I said to Mike
earlier, we want to get to know these
guys as much as possible. So, as much
exposure as we can have um you know with
you know whether it's a tackle, whether
it's a edge rusher, a linebacker, like
we want to get close to these guys. We
want to get to know them not only as
players but but as people as well.
>> And it feels like every year each draft
kind of takes on a different personality
like whether it's a quarterback year,
pass rush year, old, young. just as
you've gotten further and further into
the evaluation, what is your biggest
takeaway about this class?
>> Um, you know, I think there's some guys
in this class that we're really excited
about and I think, you know, that goes
from first round all the way down to
sixth round. You know, we don't have a
seventh rounder this year. Um, so, you
know, I think it's our job to pinpoint
exactly in those rounds who we have
conviction on who was our type of guy
that fits our scheme, but is also going
to fit our culture, um, fit fit in our
locker room and, you know, again, have
that same type of passion that we that
we've been talking about.
>> Dan, you guys, uh, had to release Asan
to open up cap space. He was a pretty
big part of that defensive front. How do
you feel about that group, but also how
do you feel about the group in the draft
at that like three tech, five tech?
>> Yeah. Um, yeah, Asan, great dude, great
leader. Um, we'll definitely miss him
around here. Uh, it's definitely just
part of the business. Um, but you know,
in terms of the defensive tackle class,
I feel pretty good about it. I think
it's a little topheavy. Um, but I do
think there's guys that we that we like
that we've kind of pinpointed that we
like. Um, so I think if the opportunity
arises, we would definitely add
competition and depth there. Um, you
know, just like every other position.
>> And kind of building off that, Brandt
told us that y'all would have to make
some room, the salary cap room. What's
the timeline for those decisions?
>> Um, th those are things that we talk
through on a daily basis. you know, when
we have to make the move, we'll we'll
make the move. But, um, you know,
there's different ways to to go about
that and figure it it out. And, you
know, luckily I Brandt Brandt's really
good at that. And, you know, myself and
him and Coach Canal is collaborating.
You know, we'll figure a way.
>> You've moved up and down the board in in
both drafts. This is a draft where a lot
of teams have multiple first round
picks, multiple second round picks. Does
that make it easier to have those draft
trade conversations or does it make it
so that maybe you kind of can figure out
what other teams are doing from the
standpoint of double dipping and and
moving around?
>> Um, you know, I I know we don't really
look at it like that. Like we're, you
know, even if a team has, you know, one
second round pick, it doesn't matter.
like we're we're always going to be
watching our board, seeing guys fall off
the board. And as they fall off the
board, you know, if we feel like we need
to make a move because maybe there's one
person at a position that we really like
that's left, then we'll make a move if
we feel like we need to make a move at
that time.
>> Does the fact that you drafted a first
round receiver two years in a row make
it less likely that you would do that
again?
>> No, I think um you know, with anything,
we're going to take the best player. So,
if the best player we feel is that at
19, I wouldn't hesitate to draft another
wide out. You know, I don't think
there's a rule that says you can't draft
a wide receiver three years in a row.
So, I'm not really going to uh you know,
I'm not going to box us in and and say
we're not going to draft one.
>> I think you've had several in the
building. What do you think of that that
group?
>> I think it's a good group. Um, you know,
I think receiver, you know, I think with
all the seven on seven camps and kids
growing up, like I feel like every year
there's like wide outs that are super
talented guys that are um, you know, you
can tell they've been doing it a long
time. So, I think it's another good
class of wide outs and you know, I think
you'll continue to see it that way.
>> Tight ends.
>> Yeah, I think tight ends, you know, I
think there's a couple guys that are
talented guys. Um, I do think, you know,
there's some depth in the later rounds
as well. So, um, again, if if they're
the best player at a certain point, we
wouldn't hesitate.
>> Dan, uh, you've had a couple
quarterbacks come on 30 visits this off
season. Um, is that a product of
evaluating them from a skill position
perspective, from seeing if they're a
cultural fit? Are you looking to draft a
quarterback in the later rounds? Can you
kind of just take me through your
>> um Yeah, I think like bringing those
guys in and bringing any guy that we
bring in on a 30 visit, you know, it
could be for medical, it can be because
we just want to get to know them a
little better. We want to see how smart
they are, you know, if they can handle,
you know, a big playbook, you know, and
be able to retain it. Um so there's
different reasons that we bring guys in
for 30 visits. Um, you know, but usually
it's just to, you know, get to know the
guys better and and just figure them out
a little more.
>> Dan, going back to your tight end room,
what are you looking for specifically in
this draft to kind of mesh with those
guys already in the room, but also
offset the other weapons that you have
on offense?
>> Um, I feel good about our tight end
room. Um, there's a a lot of guys in
that room that are still developing.
There's guys that have been here and we
know who they are and and they bring a
skill set that we really like. Um,
again, like at every position, we're
we're just looking for guys that fit,
you know, what we do schematically.
Um, you know, and fit with our culture.
So, um I don't know that we're looking
for any, you know, to answer your
question, like any specific like skill
set. You know, we're just looking for
players at all positions that that can
just make plays and really contribute to
our team and our locker room.
>> What's your outlook on the nickel
position,
big nickel or just your base set, but
also the post position in your defense?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, I think th those are
areas that we've talked about and um, we
do have some guys that we like that have
played and and show they can play at
that. Um, but again, I'm going to keep
repeating myself like if you know the
opportunity arises and there's a post
safety that we like, then great, you
know, we take a post safety. If there's
a nickel that we really like and um, at
a certain point, then yeah, we'll do
that as well. So, I'm really, you know,
myself and my staff and coach Canal,
like we're all open to just drafting the
best players that are on the board at
the current moment.
>> To follow up on that, I know the pick
comes down to you, but there are premium
positions and they're nonp premium
positions. Do you feel like if there's a
safety there or a tight end that falls
and they are the best player on your
board that you feel comfortable given,
you know, the analytics department and
all the value and all that stuff that
you're willing to make a pick there?
>> Yeah, I mean, those are all things that
we talk through and, you know, we we
discuss it and everybody has a voice in
the room and everybody gives their
opinions. Yes, ultimately I'm going to
have to make the decision, but at the
end of the day, um it's a collaborative
effort. We're all talking through all
these scenarios, all the value. Um
those are all things we understand and
you know, again, we wouldn't hesitate to
to take a guy if we feel he's the best
player. with where you are and, you
know, heading into year three, do you
think you'd be more inclined to to move
back, collect picks, or go up for a guy?
>> Um, I think we
philosophically we have an open-minded
mindset. So again, like we're open to
anything, whether it's moving back, um
whether it's moving up, you know, if we
feel like a guy can be an impact player
for us, I do think all options are on
the table.
>> Dan, when you talk about bringing guys
in and getting to know him, what can a
guy do during that visit to get your
attention in a positive way? Um, you
know, I think it's really the way again
they're going to make a lot of contact
around the building, whether it's with
our strength and conditioning, our
medical staff, um, our coaches, our the
personnel staff. Like, there's going to
be a lot of people that are going to
interact with them during the day. Um,
we usually get together afterwards and
talk talk that through and, hey, what
did you think of the guy? What' you
think of that guy? uh we go around and
get their opinions and you know maybe
they act one way with me but you know
with the trainer or something they're
you know not as not as good of a guy. So
yeah I think it's really just to bring
the guys in and like get to know them a
little more but not just me not just
coach Canalis but like is he going to be
a fit in our building
>> is the biggest thing. Couple more.
>> Go back to tight end. If how much has
Bryce you think missed having that big
target um in the middle of the field
especially as far as able to expand what
he can do?
>> Yeah. You know, I think we have some
guys on our roster that are that are big
targets. Um you know, I think in
general, you know, we have guys in our
tight end room that that we feel are
good players and and guys that have the
skill set to be able to do that. And you
know, I think opportunity, whether it's
opportunity or whether guys are still
developing, um, you know, I think we we
have the pieces in that room to be able
to do that.
>> Do you know which players will not be
available for OTAAS?
>> Uh, no, don't really know that yet. Um,
still working through. I think obviously
Icky, you know, won't be available. Um,
but I think pretty much the rest of the
roster I think is looking in pretty good
shape for that.
>> JT,
>> yeah, JT is doing great. Uh, he's
running running, cutting, looking good.
So, um, optimistic.
>> You said you started with 600. How many
names are you down to now?
>> Oh, I'm not going to I'm not going to
give you that number. It's easier to
give the big number, but I'm not going
to give you where we're at right now.
But it's in a good spot.
Anything else?
>> Thanks, man.
>> Yep.
>> Thanks, guys.